Hello everyone, welcome back.
Next up is the third part of our live stream,
which is Qiang's sharing.
Everyone, please give Qiang a big hand.
Hehe.
I'm trying to figure it out myself.
Is it good?
Okay, I'll start.
Okay, okay.
Hello everyone, I'm Xiao Zhiqiang.
Today I'm going to share a little bit of my experience as an MD.
Because I've been using MD for a long time,
I'm currently working on games,
and I've worked on movies and animation before.
Is my voice okay? Is the volume okay?
Hello?
It should be okay.
I think it's okay.
Okay, okay.
And then...
This is my A-stand,
because I also do a lot of
game art.
And then these are some,
just some simple introductions.
Right now,
because I've been using MD for about
one...
one and a few years.
One...
two years,
one and three years.
It's been a long time.
Because,
I've always felt that MD has changed my workflow.
Before, I was all about
using Zbrush to carve,
but later,
later on,
I started to use MD on a large scale,
so I feel that it can
help me improve my performance.
And,
for example,
if you want to carve something,
it takes a lot of time,
and you need to find a lot of references.
But,
MD brings you
a...
a detailed analysis.
It can get some
very real
textures.
For example,
this character was made
a few months ago.
It...
Look at these little wrinkles,
these little things,
including the hat.
I basically made it with MD all over my body.
It's definitely not shoes.
I made the shoes with MD.
And then,
this is the final result.
this is...
Zbrush,
some of the renderings I made.
This is...
It seems to be Kisa's renderings.
Because,
Guangshu made a render for me.
I don't really understand renderings.
So,
I will...
Sometimes,
I will ask Guangshu
to make some renderings for me.
This is my own renderings.
My own renderings
are relatively bad.
I will make some
simple renderings
for you.
And then,
some...
You see,
MD can make
this kind of character.
It can also make
this kind of...
This kind of bulletproof vest.
You see,
all the things
in the bulletproof vest
are made
by Marvelous.
These...
Some...
Some effects.
I think,
because if you brush it,
it will take a lot of time
to brush it.
But,
you can get some
wonderful details
from MD.
It's...
Relatively,
it's very simple.
But,
the final result
is very good.
You see,
all the little things
are solved
in Marvelous,
including some
little pins
and stuff.
And then,
you can make some backpacks
through Marvelous.
This is also
a...
A...
An effect of Marvelous.
It's completely Marvelous.
But,
although it's also made by Guangshu,
I didn't divide it
into UVs
or anything.
I mainly
used
a program
in Kitsart.
A program
made by Kitsart.
I didn't do
a lot of
advanced stuff.
I think it should be
OK.
It should be OK.
You see,
this is
a...
A...
An effect of Marvelous.
I think
that
now,
more and more
gamers
or
movie fans
are also
starting
to use
Marvelous
for some
creation.
For some creation.
I think that
it's really
improving our efficiency.
Today,
I'm going to make
a simple
outfit.
This is...
I made
a simple
thing.
Because I saw
they both made
some clothes.
So,
Marvelous can make
some very interesting things.
You can make
some animation.
You see,
it's
like
the ones
on the side
of the mall.
They're all OK.
Because I'm
working in Tangxun now.
So,
I'm going to make some...
I'm not saying it's an advertisement.
OK.
So,
let's start
today's
introduction.
I'm going to make
a...
Is the time
enough?
Yes,
it is.
It's definitely enough.
Yes.
Because I'm a quick-witted person.
I speak
faster.
We're going to make
a simple
outfit.
Because
many people
may think that
this is
a simple outfit.
So,
I'm going to
show you
some
small ways
to help you
see how to
improve
some efficiency.
Because
it's long.
It's like
an accordion.
OK.
Let's start now.
I recorded
my
video
in advance.
Most of
my
situations
involve
a basic
human body.
Because
for many times,
many people
can't see
the basic human body
from the outside.
I think there are
some settings
because
the sound
will be low.
Because
many people
can't see
the basic human body
because it's too big
or too small.
Because I think
Marble is a
physical software
and it's the same
as other rendering software.
If you know rendering,
you know that
the size of my model
shouldn't be too big
or too small.
It must be in line
with this
physical principle.
You can
calculate
the size
of my model
in 3D.
So,
Marble is the same.
you need to match
the size
of your model
with the size
of your model.
This is very important.
You need to match
the size
of your model.
This is very important.
Then,
I usually
look for
some
material
on the website
because
for
people
who are not
in the fashion industry,
we don't
have much
information.
So,
I will show
you
how to
make
a
basic
model.
You can
find
it
through
any
search engine.
Right?
A t-shirt
or a
pants
are all
very
easy
to get.
Then,
according to
this
kind of
background
picture,
you can
make
a very
simple
model.
Actually,
this step
is relatively
simple
because
Marble
can
make
these
models
very well.
Actually,
I think it's
similar to
PS
or some
other
2D
software.
You can think
about it
through
this
idea.
So,
you can
adjust
the
outline
and
the
background
to a
better
match.
You can
also
add
this
controllable
point
to make
it
more
perfect.
Many
people
have thought too much
when making MD.
I think
it's
like,
oh,
use this
and that.
Don't
think too much
about it.
You just
make this
very basic
thing
and
that's it.
Don't
add a lot of
fancy things.
Make the
foundation first.
The foundation
is very
important.
Then,
I will
merge
these two
things.
I think
I have
one such
version.
For example,
the last
details,
basically,
it's okay to
deal with it
later.
Then,
I will
clean up
these points
and then
go again.
I promise
because
I saw
Surrey
talking about
it.
There are a lot of
you will find
too many
points on the edge.
I will
maximize
the
outline
of this
point
to control
at least one
because
you can
control it better
when it's
too much.
It's
hard to
control it.
You see,
I will get
a basic
style.
Then,
I will
do a
simple
collection
until
I and
the human body
compare
to
get a
size that I
want.
Then,
in fact,
this step is very
important.
That is,
when you do
these things
well,
you will
include
you see
this kind of
edge
41.3
and 38.2
when we
do some
sewing.
That is,
my clothes
must be
the same size,
right?
You see,
this 41
this 38
I will adjust
this point later
so that its
distance is the same
because
it has a
I don't know
how to say
this kind of thing.
There is a
theory
that you must
remember
all of
these
sizes
to be reasonable.
If you
don't
agree,
your clothes
will become
unbalanced
and produce
some very
strange
and uneven
wrinkles.
Just like
you buy clothes,
I also hope that your clothes
are very
flat,
right?
It's impossible to
sew
and sew
the place
becomes
very strange
and ugly.
Including
places like this,
I will
choose two lines
and then
it will
show
the distance
of these two lines
and then
I will choose
this line
to see
what is the size
of its line
and then
let the two
banana
boxes
be the
distance of this line.
This is
a question I have to consider.
It's still
a very
bottom-down
thing
because
MD can
show
very well
the distance
of this line.
You see,
this distance
is 23
and more.
These are
very
intuitive
to show.
Because I think
today I heard
a lot of
clothing experts
I don't know
or
others
because I don't know
how many
gamers there are.
Then I will
mirror
the other
part I want
and then
I will
re-create
this semi-transparent
and then
I will spend
some time
on this
to verify
that
it will
ah
flip
its
background
because
when you flip
it, MD
has a
setting
that you can
change
its
front
panel
and
the color of the back panel
can make you
see more clearly
you can
open both sides
see better and see better
you can see better and better
than the previous
and that
the previous
and the future
is a relationship
ah
I will
freeze
other parts
ah
freeze
the
game
I don't
play any
game
we just
make models
do
it
ah
oh
then
I will update it now
After you've created the version, you can very directly
integrate it through this three-dimensional system.
We're not fishers.
It's very hard work.
And look, I'll see if the distance between me and the front and the back is the same.
This is very important.
You see, when I'm calculating, I'm just calculating my clothes.
Other things, including sleeves and hats, I'll make some clashes.
Don't hurry to make clashes.
I think you should make clashes little by little first.
I might be different from many people.
Maybe some people like to make clashes together.
My work habit is to make clashes little by little.
Make clashes in other places first,
and then make clashes little by little.
Because when you have very few pieces of paper,
you can calculate very quickly.
If you have too many pieces of paper,
it will be very laggy.
Then I'll put the sleeves here.
And then I'll make some clashes with some free sewing.
I think this free sewing tool is also very useful.
It can choose my distance very well.
And then I'll make the same for this side and this side.
You see, a lot of people are calculating clothes like this.
And then I'll make some clashes with this side.
Then my hands will be like this.
For example, when someone is doing this kind of foraging,
He likes sewing the sleeves from the bottom right off the contest.
I'll not sew the besides.
I'll wait for him to finish calculating,
and let him continue sewing it.
If he can't wear it like this,
you'll eventually have to wear the sleeves and the clothes together.
Hey, keep choosing the front and back of your sewing.
You'll have a better effect.
Cockpile styles avoiding MD calculation
It should be okay, because it can pour in some things to do the calculation, but it's okay to do the calculation, because at least I heard that when追光 was doing the little god, they used this method to do it, which is to pour a model made by Maya into the marbler for a calculation, but it's different.
Then I'm going to do some of them through this free sewing tool, and then I'm going to sew them together with this hat.
Yes, there is no 2D version of the pour in, and there is no way to modify it.
The UV is also okay, but sometimes there are some shapes that are not good, and there is no way to do some.
There is no way to make some modifications or anything.
If I say that for some controllability, I must still hope that I will do some molding in the marbler.
If this is the case, I may operate it better.
Because this piece, you see, there are some errors, it will produce some strange things like this.
It may be that I chose a small piece more.
Then just do some seam allowances and change it.
You see, including now, I didn't go to the other side, right?
Don't worry.
If you do this side well, you can right-click to copy another one.
Copy one.
It has a link to copy.
You can put that one.
Put that one.
That's my one.
The seam allowances can be poured together.
Then.
I will enlarge this.
You see, there are many times, many people like to pull it.
Because when pulling, there will often be some errors.
So in many cases, when my model is ok, I will directly change my horizontal and vertical stretch ratio.
Or you see, there are several ways.
Or you can do some stretch like this.
To get the size that I want.
Don't talk nonsense.
It's so scary.
Ah Dong, who are you?
Ah Dong.
Then still.
Because it is related to the left and right directions.
So you just choose half to be compressed.
You will get both sides at the same time.
Some of that.
Expansion.
I don't even know myself.
Okay, you see.
When we are doing MD, we must remember this.
To do this kind of basic thing.
To do this kind of basic thing first.
Do it well first.
The basic appearance.
You do all these clothes or whatever.
Don't think about any details first.
Just like you do the model.
Don't think about the details of the model first.
Do this kind of big relationship first.
I don't know how many people have learned to draw.
People who draw are also.
When we are drawing, we first draw this kind of big structure.
Then go to the small details inside.
So this thing is.
It's the same at any time.
When we are doing the model.
We also have to consider this kind of thing.
If you want to do a big structure first.
Then think about it little by little.
How to add details later.
This is very, very important.
I hope everyone can listen to it.
Because I also talked to Sarah about this kind of thing.
The people who learn fashion.
What they understand.
It's different from what we do in the game.
In our game, we need to consider more.
How can I get a better effect in the game?
Instead of saying that this dress must be completely matching.
How suitable is this kind of dress?
It's not like that.
What kind of role do we apply in the game?
For example, this kind of joint needs more wrinkles.
It's the kind of thing that often moves.
Because after all.
If there are a lot of people playing games.
You know that their wrinkles are not this kind of real-time changes.
They are dead.
When I do any sports.
His wrinkles are still like this.
You see, I started to consider adding some details.
Right?
This kind of clothes.
What kind of closing?
And then at the same time.
When I'm calculating this kind of thing.
I'm going to move other places.
You have to learn.
How do you better control this software?
This is very important.
And then I put these two sides.
You see.
To do a.
Unlock.
And then to pull.
In this way.
It will be very good.
If you put everything.
Just like that situation.
I put this.
When I'm doing some calculations.
It will.
It will fly away.
Including.
You see.
In this case.
If there is a problem.
It's hard to pull.
I'll take this.
This.
Go first.
Give him.
Cancel the seam.
Because in this way.
A piece.
On this arm.
Just better.
Can do better.
Some.
Avoid.
This mistake.
And then.
Do some seam.
Including the bottom.
It's the same.
Do some seam.
To pull.
Get a.
One.
We want.
A.
A R.
As.
I.
See.
You know.
What I'm talking about.
Is.
You got a.
Self.
M.
About.
The.
Bad.
Fault.
So.
How are you.
How was you.
Very.
Yes.
So.
Now.
Take.
to make the ratio of the layers smaller.
For example, 90 or 95 is equal to left and right.
Then I will copy the other one
and put it under the clothes.
What is intelligent固化?
I will remake this version
and do some sewing on it.
I will mirror the other one
and sew them together.
Then I will copy the other one
and do some sewing on it.
I think this is what work is all about.
There are many things you need to do manually.
If everything is completely automated,
what do we need to do?
Actually, all of my operations
are more conventional.
There are not many strange functions.
Many people think MD is difficult.
Actually, there are only a few functions that you often use.
There are not many things
that you need to consider.
Actually, many people think
I used this and that again.
Actually, many people think I used this and that again.
I see why you do not accept.
I see what you mean.
You will find the basic and good way.
其实所有的这些基础都是在这儿来去搞定的 然后对于有些形态你觉得不太好的 你再进行一些调整 比如说这种距离感 让它是一致的 比如12点多少 然后这个我就会调的跟那个是一样的
然后左右距离是一样的 然后再把这个边缘再调大点 就是一点一点的去进行微调了 一点一点去进行微调
很多人已经开始用10啊11啊 其实我的软件是在有一年的Marvel的一个比赛中去得到的 去赢的
然后我就一直使用 更新之后我就一直使用9.5
我觉得9.5给我的感觉是最好的 我还没有去用其他的一个版本 因为很多人用一些
嗯
一一级一级的版本了 其实我觉得9.5对我来说是非常好的 就是更新到10.0之后 我有很多东西都哎 我都不知道在哪儿 所以我又回来用9点9.5的一个一个一个软件
然后大部分情况下
就是在调整完这种基础得到基础的版片之后就开始去啊对他的一些小的东西进行一些调整啊什么的
嗯
哎呀我刚才抽奖没抽到你们都抽到了我也没抽到
我也一直在打打公屏我没抽到
然后你看我想在中间加一条这种拉链然后你会看到我我选择三条边之后然后你会得到一个长度然后直接你去建一个这个长度的东西就好
嗯
我再去建一个比如说75.53
然后我会建一个这种长条
增加了一半的时间
就其实拓扑就看你吸用了什么东西了
我希望要一个什么样的拓扑一会我玛雅会讲一个
啊一点点我会有一个小小的一个演示啊就是怎么去处理啊吗
倒倒出去的东西
就是就看你是在哪进行一个应用你是应用在动画也好游戏也好或者什么也好啊
嗯
然后我通过这种自由缝合的一个
工具去进行一些缝合
导入在导入你接下来是要说导入这不二是吧
你看这样我就得到一个这种效果
因为很多人就不会忽略这一条就直接连了其实对于一些项目来讲我这会有一些拉链呢我会后期通过一些方法去做一些东西
打个字都这么费劲
帮不帮218
竹子218呀
然后你看我会绘制一个新的一个版片
作为到时候这种胸前的一个口袋
应该会有录播吧
我的教程不是白买的谁的教程
然后进行一些缝合
去得到这个口袋的一个模型
导入JP咋设置
一会儿有啊一会有别急
一会儿有啊一会儿有别急
我不打广告了
好好好
咳咳
Adjust the size of the clothes.
If you feel the clothes are too tight,
I will make it a little bit bigger.
Some people will think about whether to make it a little bit bigger.
Am I right?
I am saying the same thing again.
I am looking at this chat and I am already destroyed.
How do I design the JV?
I will use this information
to create something,
and merge them together.
What kind of version do you want to get?
There are many people who have this little blue line after merging,
and there will always be people who will use this little shield,
and you can choose which one to use.
And then include this one and merge it again.
Because in this case,
this thing is to make a division first,
and then merge them together to get one.
Is that right?
Because sometimes when you say a certain word,
people will say, where is it?
You can explain it to them.
You can find a similar shield,
and you can know which one it is.
That's it.
I'll be advertising later.
Don't worry.
Let's learn something first.
To do everything,
I hope that everyone
is not in a hurry to do it.
Think about these things first.
Make some seam allowances.
This dress may be down the whole
I did it for about an hour.
Almost a little bit.
Let's do it again.
Many people use it.
I don't know why.
Because me and Uncle Guang also have some courses,
but I don't have it now.
It's mainly for the game industry,
but many people feel that it's strange.
There are some ideas.
That's it.
Well, I think it's good.
Yes, it's a good case. I will add DRC to the kids later.
This is MD official, don't say too much.
And then do some pull-ups.
Sometimes, when I'm talking about something, a lot of people think,
Hey, why do you need to think about something when you're pulling up?
Actually, I think MD is a program-based software.
And then a lot of things you get is a very random thing.
But I think some things are controllable.
It's like I use MD, I will apply it to a lot of art.
Because a lot of people do MD, I also see a lot of MD works.
And then I found out that they have a lot of them.
That is,
Maybe a lot of people think that MD is a software.
I can get one.
This sentence is very weird.
Pull-ups, not what to think about when pulling up.
When pulling up, maybe I'll look at my phone.
When we are,
We'll talk about that later.
You see, when I get a foundation,
When I get a very,
When I think my version is very good,
I will start to consider how to add some details to this dress.
Add some details.
And then you see, I will use this pen tool to draw this kind of support line.
I think sometimes this kind of support line is very important.
Because I'm thinking about how big and small the pocket is.
I can do some drawing through this kind of support line.
Because in this way, I can know
Hey, I should do something big and small.
In fact, this kind of support line is also related to clothes and human body.
It also has to do with you going to control the point at that time.
Because a lot of people are doing this kind of thing.
When it comes to adding support lines,
For me, I, because I am,
I am doing film and television,
I can also do games.
When I do film and television,
Maybe more of it is for this kind of actor.
One of the sound materials to do,
For this kind of reference,
To carry out production.
But when I do games,
Maybe because film and television is,
Film and television is in the movie.
There are all kinds of special films.
I don't know if you have seen it.
I'll talk about some of the projects I've done.
And then I'll introduce you to some of the things I've done.
But for games,
It's all dead.
So I'm going to think a lot about it.
Hey, after I finish this model,
What should it look like?
Because for these joints,
There will be some small demonstrations later.
How do I get some of the joints?
Some of the joints.
You see, I'll draw a support line.
So I know where it is.
Right?
And then I'll go through this.
Some cutting here.
It's still that sentence.
Do the whole thing.
Right?
And then through.
Divide again.
Get some more detailed things.
Because you.
The big frame is good.
You're going to tear down the little things.
It's going to be very simple.
If you just started.
You're thinking about this.
Some strange panels.
You'll never get any good results.
So you see.
I'll do the whole thing first.
And then we're going to divide.
And then we're going to tear down the things.
And then we're going to merge.
So I get all kinds of panels.
I don't know if you can understand it.
You see, I'm going to sew.
Look, I got it.
I got this panel.
If you ask me to imagine this panel in vain.
It's hard for me to imagine.
What kind of panel it is.
And then I'm going to rotate it.
I'm going to.
I'm going to make some seams for them.
Actually, a lot of people think that my clothes look so complicated.
All the clothes we can imagine.
It's just a t-shirt, just a long-sleeved sweater.
Right?
You do it again after you do it.
And then we're going to make some sections.
So that's it.
You see me to prevent any mistakes.
I copied a new one.
And then I'm going to do some.
I'm going to delete some of that, and then I'm going to sew them together, merge these two things.
You see, it will automatically calculate such a structure.
You see, I got a pretty good one like this.
Because there are a lot of our hats that are this shape.
Everyone can see these clothes in real life, right?
Then I have to re-sew these things together.
You have to remember to do a whole thing, and then do this little thing little by little.
What is the meaning of cutting this kind of board?
Some clothes are made like this.
What do you think the meaning of cutting is?
Some clothes are shaped like this.
Because, for example, when you play games,
there must be this kind of clothes.
I should have done it like this.
I don't know what you want to ask.
Yes.
In order to match with the original painting,
then I go to the mirror and get the other side.
You see, I don't give myself trouble.
Don't give yourself trouble.
Do one side, then do the other side.
This is also very good.
I got it.
You see, this way I got a better structure
to match with our original painting or whatever.
In fact, many people who play games are not born in fashion design.
So it's hard for us to understand what this board is.
What is that board?
So we will use some other methods
to get the design or design of the clothes
that are needed in the project.
And then we will do some pull-ups.
And then we will do some connections.
Because for me, there may be a lot of special terms in fashion design.
Or how to do some pull-ups.
It's hard to understand.
You see, for now,
for many games,
do I need some pull-ups here?
Right?
Because this looks good.
And this is what I'm talking about.
Many people add a lot of pull-ups.
In fact, for some projects,
what I need more is this one.
There are some pull-ups here.
There are a lot of...
Let me see if there are any pictures.
There are a lot of projects.
In fact, I need...
This is...
Those were some videos just now.
No.
In fact, in fashion design,
you can make some better cases.
For example,
when a lot of people do some projects,
you will find,
like this kind of pants,
or...
These are some good examples.
When we are doing a project,
I need to consider...
Here, you see, there are some pull-ups.
Here, a little loose.
There are some pull-ups here.
There are some pull-ups below.
You need to apply this...
The art stuff is here.
There are some pull-ups, pull-ups, pull-ups, pull-ups.
You need to have some good rhythm.
When you do anything,
when you look at the real world,
there will be some good cases to refer to.
Moreover,
when you do more pull-ups here,
you need to bend your knees all the time.
You need to bend your knees all the time.
So, I hope it will have this kind of pull-ups in the future.
But this one has always been...
It won't lead to too many things.
So, for me,
it's relatively smooth.
So, when you do pull-ups,
there will be some techniques.
You need to apply the art stuff in it.
There are some simple,
complicated,
simple, complicated,
this kind of comparison relationship in it.
If you do a lot of pull-ups for everything,
it will become particularly complicated.
It will also become...
It will become...
It will be ugly.
It's not good.
You need to have some of these pretty things in it.
Look, I really want to have a lot of pull-ups here.
So, how can I get this thing done?
I will definitely need
to bend this kind of elbow joint, right?
Bend the elbow joint,
and I will get a pull-up like this.
So, in general,
I will make another one like this
outside,
a blank shape like this one.
So, I will make another one like this outside,
Do you have any advice for people who are interested in this project?
For this project, I have encountered too many of these situations.
Everyone hopes that this project will be successful.
But why are there no joints?
This is too bad.
And in the future, it may not be able to be used in animation or anything.
Do you have any advice for people who are interested in this project?
When I record this, what am I doing?
I will look for a lot of references to look at these small details.
I will look for some references.
You see, I started to think about how to make references to the edges.
To add some details.
I will talk about the joints later.
A little bit.
There will be some details on this side as well.
I will add some details.
I will merge these two.
It's fine, I will share it to you at the end.
Remove.
Including my Billy Billy.
I am also a random artist.
I rarely go to the studio.
When I think about it, I will probably do a live broadcast.
Occasionally.
Including these.
I will add some small details.
Including a little less.
Because it is very helpful in the later processing.
Offset.
Anyone in the showroom please use the editing motors.
Let see.
Offset.
I always like to use the editing motors.
For random stream.
I am open like I am random.
When I remember it, I suddenly streaming, but don'tbins advertising.
Who sees it, then dosen't.
This form.
Usually I'm also working.
I may not have too much time to do things like this.
You see, I haven't changed it to a fabric attribute until now.
not going to change its examples.
Don't worry.
一點一點來啊一點一點來包括你看現在就像這種拉鍊我會給他一個比較硬的一個材質就是很多人在做衣服的時候都喜歡給他一個材質你要給他不同的材質讓他產生一些比較有趣的一些變化啊
你看這增加一些這種這種細節
而且很多人喜歡比如說這種收口啊他們喜歡做一些折邊
就做出那種因為我們這種鬆緊的會有一些很小的細節都喜歡在MP裏做
我一般不會在MD裏做我會後期在瑪雅中進行處理因為後期你可以很簡單的處理這些在MD中你反而得不到更好的效果啊
你看去增加這些這些小的細節有的時候這種不好我會給他進行一些伸出
我本來想在這加的然後因為他自動呢就會出現這種問題我後來就刪掉了當然當然你可以手動的去進行一些繪紙啊因為你可以繪紙內部線啊或怎麼去得到啊
嗯
然後進行一些簡單拉扯
包括你看就袖口還有這種收口我會給他一些硬一點的材質因為這種地方的材質肯定和衣服是不一樣的對吧你這樣的話就可以得到一些比較有趣的一些效果啊
然后你看包括帽子我可以進行一些給他摘下來
嗯
我覺得MD是一個讓你很就是需要你去安安靜靜的去
做一會兒的一些軟件啊
你看我有的時候可能會拼一些點拿去什麼的去處理一下去進行一些拉扯
稍微倒一點啊是不是我們是到幾點
啊到幾點都可以的到幾點都可以的因為大家有問題要吃飯的一會要吃飯啊ok
然後你看我在這種情況下
很多人做帽子呢就是
其實要做兩層啊
卡咋整
卡我到很少碰進卡有很多人就說老是我卡咋整我很少碰進卡你看我會複製到
新的一層然後給他翻轉一下發現因為這樣的話你會得到一個比較好的效果也比較真實的因為畢竟帽子是兩層你看剛才
挺不起來現在你的帽子就停起來了而且裡面還會有一些小的細節在這對吧
通宵
我跟你講你要是我講我可以一直講
因為我平時我也我也是我也是講課
熬陰一樣我今天沒有sp教學啊因為新的大哥都講完了然後我主要是麻煩的東西我不會講一些sometimes東西了啊
啊
雙層是非常有用的啊你看我然後發畫一個內部線包括這個你想像它是一個拉鏈我可以把它哎給他分開
然后我再接著進行一些縫合
就拉鏈我沒有做拉鏈啊有的時候會
會有些人會在麻煩了的做一些拉鏈我會做一些假的東西在這就代替拉鏈就好了
我不會說
真做一個拉鏈你看我這塊需要控制一些這個拼一些點進行一些控制進行一些拉扯得到我想要的一些效果因為
對於下面上來講當然需要
遊戲來講就需要一些比較好的這個外輪過我們稱為叫西路外就是這種輪廓感
所以說我會通過這種拉鏈拉扯你看側面會有這種輪廓感如果你貼脖子上就會變得很單調因為這樣的話它會有一個比較好的輪廓感啊是這個
都有很多模型制
比如說
用 generation
我有没有出过教程可能教程出太多了
因為一會我会介紹啊我不知道有多少人听过模型制
然后进行一些修改
直接c进入模型制
然后GTAC进入直播间还行,对摩星志了解一下,光束了解一下,对我们俩是一个组织啊,你看,然后我会去进行一些拉扯,得到我希望要的一个效果,因为还是你在拉的时候也是要考虑到,
我们这种现实生活中的这个拉链,在打开的时候是一个什么样的状态,基本是往外外翻的一个状态,对不对,就是这样去考虑啊,动画我不是很了解啊,可能Siri可以帮你去解释一下,
那是吗,下次我再,
然后包括现阶段,
我会把,
它如果说我直接复制一个内部层的话,它会把每条线都进行一些缝合,就把所有的线都进行一些缝合,但是呢,我不希望所有的进行缝合,我只是把这个中间我肯定不希望缝合,对不对,我只需要把这个外轮廓进行缝合,所以说我会把内部的这个缝线全都给它删除掉,然后再去做一个这种重新缝一下啊,去调整一下,
就是这个时候就需要仔细一点,因为毕竟有很多时候它这个里边的线有点多,你会那个什么一点啊,
你能来强给给你好,
你问问光说,下回我帮你问问光说,
其实如果说大家在上海的话,就经常能看你光说啊,就我们园区经常有人会在我QQ群里会说,哎,那个前面我看见你了,我说下回你能不能出来,你跟我打个招呼,有种感觉是你们在暗处,我在明处,这很吓人啊,
然后对对这个,你看我连的时候就有些错误,我会把很多东西重新再删除,再重新连一遍啊,
然后我会把其他地方都隐藏,因为这样是更易于我们,
那个更易于我们这种调整啊,
我太吓人了,你不要这我你们这搞得我这很很很害怕呀,
然后再重新进行一些连接,
其实啊,有很多时候,包括这种双层啊,你都可以得到一些特别好的一些效果,
包括我看刚才有人说啊,有人做要,
问siri那个羽绒服的一些材质什么的,就是这种双层你可以做一个很棒的羽绒服出来啊,
一会儿我可以简单给大家演示一下,你看这样我就得到一个很好的一个内部的一个东西,
然后还有一点小技巧,就是比如我把所有都显示出来,
还有一个小技巧,我希望里边,因为对于很多衣服来讲,里边可能会有更多的衣服,
所以说我可以强制的对于里边做一个更好的一个放大,
让它横向纵向有一个更大的一个效果,这样这样的话里边有一个更多的一个堆积啊,
OK,我记得演示一下一会儿,你看这样的话我会得到一个比较好的效果,
你看这个边缘也非常的好看啊,比你单一层要好很多,对吧,
而且这儿我会拼一个点,然后去手动的去调整我想要的一个外裸裤,
其实我很多时候,我会把这个外裸裤弄得比较好看,
我会把这个外裸裤弄得比较好看,
就是有时候会做这种帽衫,我觉得怎么说呢?
就是有很多人对于这种帽子的这种做老是做不好啊,
老是做不好所以我很多时候就做这种东西,一会儿我会演示一点点其他的,
是吗?虚拟偶像,我不太清楚虚拟偶像这种东西啊,
因为跨行,隔行如隔山,我觉得很多时候都不太懂其他的,
有可能接下来我更多的发挥吗,
I want to learn more about how to solve this kind of thing.
Because the model is not that complicated, right?
Including this one, I want it to be tighter.
Yes, you have to wear a hat every day, or you'll be recognized.
It's scary, isn't it?
And when I was watching Siri play the female lead,
I found that the distance between her body and her clothes was relatively large.
In fact, when you choose a body, there is an offset.
You can adjust it a little bit lower, and I'll show it to you in a moment.
And then you see, I'm thinking about it now.
I should be. I don't know what it is when I record.
I have to consider how to do it if I want more wrinkles here.
I'll go a little bit further ahead.
And then, yes, I think because when we make clothes,
a lot of people want to know what kind of material I have.
I have so many predictions.
Which one should I use?
I've always had a lot of people.
How do you say it?
Just try it one by one, or look for various Chinese references.
Right?
You must be.
There are a lot of people who do this, right?
I won't.
I won't look for a lot of reference.
I will like a person myself.
I think this is very good.
I think it's very good.
I used to post it on the public number.
If you follow the public number of the model system, you will see it.
This person is Jed Law.
He has one.
He has one of this Marvler's reference guide.
He did a calculation of all the material properties of Marvler.
You can see very objectively what kind of property each material gets.
Very, very intuitive.
Because you may not be able to calculate it when you are calculating.
But you can see this picture very objectively.
What kind of property do I need?
That's it.
This is very good.
I've been using this.
I won't say.
Look at this.
Look at that.
I'll post it in the chat.
Can I post it in the chat?
I don't know.
Wait a minute.
Because my video may not be very clear.
I remember watching our video.
It seems to be connected.
Don't let it post.
Okay.
You send it to everyone.
You can go to Artstation to search for this person's name.
Okay.
We actually have this picture.
Right?
You send it to everyone.
Okay.
Yes.
Then you can see very objectively the property of the material you want.
Because you can see what his posture is like.
So I will adjust this posture.
And then I will introduce a new model.
This step may be.
Many people.
Many people didn't see it clearly.
I'll go to my Maya and show it to everyone.
This is my basic body.
I'll save it.
Wait a minute.
Marvelous.
New.
Important.
Wait for me a little bit.
Base.
Look.
This is my basic human body.
Right?
Can you understand this?
Then I will import a base pose.
Because this human body is basically a half-bonded human body.
Half-bonded human body.
It means that we have this basic model.
Then I will import it.
For example, these two.
For example, these two, I'm going to do this for them.
You see, it has this blend shape.
In the default situation, it's like this.
And then I can do something like this in AMD.
You can understand this, right?
I don't know if you can understand this.
This is what we're doing.
I open my model.
Look, this is my model, right?
I fire import obj.
And then I import my modeler's base pose.
And then I open it.
It has a property.
In general situations, we click open,
which is to change a new body.
Add, which is to add something in.
But in this case, I choose move target.
Because I'm going to do some transformation through this model.
Right?
I click OK.
OK.
Wait a minute.
This model may have been changed.
I delete it.
Import, base, add.
This model, let me sort it out.
OK.
Fire, import obj, base pose.
Because that's something that I bend my arm.
And then it has a move target.
OK.
Look, it will automatically make some bends.
See?
This is some of the effects we want to get.
Can you understand this?
This is what you need in the game.
Hey, I need some movements here, right?
For example, I can make some adjustments on this basis.
It's possible to do some pull-ups or something.
Hey, adjust.
This is the effect I want.
It may take some time.
I'll just make a rough estimate.
Look, I want my model to be like this.
And then I'm going to solidify this thing.
For example, I can make it a little bigger or a little smaller.
It doesn't matter.
And then I'm going to import obj.
I'm going to put that base in.
And then move target.
OK.
And then I'm going to make it a little bigger.
It's like it's going back.
It's going back.
But I still get this effect.
I still get this effect.
See?
It's just that the back is a little ugly.
I'm just going to move the brush a little bit to pull it back a little bit.
Do you understand?
You can understand?
Look, if I say my arm is straight, I can't pull this effect.
Right?
But in this case, I can get some very good results.
For example, if you want to do the same with your leg, you need a few movements here.
In this case, you can use the binding as a shoulder,
so that your leg is in a squatting position.
You can do some movements here and there,
and then you can return it back, and you'll get this effect.
Do you understand?
I hope you all understand.
Then, you can do some pull-ups.
You'll get the movement you want.
When you're adjusting everything, you need to think about this.
In this game, I need to do some pull-ups for my body,
and then some movements here.
You can see that there are fewer movements here.
These are some pull-ups.
You can do some pull-ups here.
This is a rhythm.
When we're doing any kind of art, we need to have a rhythm.
Can I use the binding model?
Yes, actually, this thing...
For example, this kind of human body thing.
Look, if I have a basic model here, right?
I can direct this model to...
I can use the Muffler to make a decision.
And then, I can make another model.
I can direct this model like this.
I can use the Muffler again.
I'm good.
I don't need to do binding.
I can make some adjustments in JB, right?
Do you understand?
How do you do that kind of pull-up movement?
Pull-ups, I think Sarah Gaunt's method is very good.
She does it through...
through the body to draw this board.
Because it's completely genuine.
After it's totally genuine.
I get a model that's perfectly genuine,
and then by these horizontal, horizontal...
The big and small
And then I can alter its components.
including one of the models inside.
You can give it a different material and get a better effect.
Then I go back to Moftaki and I still keep this gesture.
What do you mean by wearing a loose dress with less body contact than a loose dress with less body contact?
What do you mean? I don't really understand.
Is there a similar picture?
OK, that was just a little bit of a sudden change.
That's what I'm talking about today.
It's about how this Marveler makes clothes.
My clothes.
My own process.
That's it.
I don't know about everyone.
I talked a little bit about some of the techniques.
I think some things are pretty useful.
I hope everyone can learn.
Next, it may become Maya's part.
Become what everyone is more concerned about.
You see, including this pocket.
I also added one.
Add a horizontal-central ratio to the selection of this board.
Make it bigger up and down.
Get some wrinkles.
Or it's completely attached.
You can.
Do it like this.
Next, I'm going to show you how to do it.
I don't do a lot of
I think there should be a lot of small ways.
He used to do some live broadcasts.
There must be a lot of things.
There are a lot of things in it.
OK.
Next, I'll use a simple case to show you how I update this thing.
How to deal with this thing.
Is it black and white?
No, it's not.
So you don't need to change it.
Is it black and white?
No.
OK.
You can see that the screen is flat.
Then you can see that I spent some time doing a simple one.
It's kind of like a
You see it in a default state that it is this one.
In a default situation, Maveler is a state with three corners.
Right?
This three-point.
So I'm generally in a situation where I will use this.
You see, I can choose the type.
You can do that at any time.
I can choose this cross, and I can directly turn it into a four-sided face.
Maybe sometimes it takes a while.
Because there are a lot of people who like to take this model directly to
CanSiri, Gantt, and Ceno, and just take this model out and do some production.
But for me, it's probably not enough for a lot of details.
We need to go outside and continue to do it.
Whether it's through JB or something else.
That's how I do it.
And then you see, I'm going to make some changes.
You see, Marble's default situation will get an effect like this.
You see, his face is like this.
Although it's a little messy, but for me, I think it's enough.
It's totally enough.
And then I get this model.
I will export this model.
export obj
I will export a model.
And then for the model, I might make these settings thin.
I can also sew, I can also not sew.
I can choose to sew, I can also choose not to sew.
And then remember to click on UV.
Remember to click on UV.
And then OK.
And then I will.
I forgot this UV editor before.
Because there was someone before.
I saw that there was a question about UV when I was talking.
You are asking about UV.
In fact, for this UV that will be updated after 9.2.
There used to be no UV editor.
Now there is a UV editor.
So there is this one.
So you choose this one in this.
Right click the second one.
Set UV from pattern.
That is, it will follow your pattern.
This pattern is to arrange your UV.
Then you just need to move it to what you want.
For example, the first line.
The second line.
You can adjust your UV here.
Just one form.
And then you go back to simulation.
I'm going to fall again.
Because I didn't fall this UV thing just now.
And then I have to fall again.
Just fall.
And then go back to our Maya.
And then I'm going to import this model.
Look, I'm going to get this model.
It's in this state.
Although the line is a little messy.
But for me, I don't think it's a big deal.
Not a big deal.
Look, this is my UV.
Right?
For the Maya part, I'll make it a little easier.
You see, I have this UV seam line for everything.
Right?
For example, I choose a seam line.
I enter a white.
Then it turns into two.
Then I'll add a line in the middle.
Then I'll move it in.
There are some operations in Maya.
Just follow the direction of the hair line.
You just press Ctrl and press the middle button.
And then just move it.
And then add a button.
Add this kind of thing.
And then make some movements.
And then squeeze some of this edge.
This is what I just did.
That's the idea.
There's someone asking me what to do if my clothes don't have thickness.
You can squeeze on it through this method.
And get some models with thickness.
But with this kind of thing.
We need a little bit of polls.
And you need to understand our clothes.
You see the clothes we wear
How do you do this kind of small pressure edge?
How do you do this kind of feeling that you press me and I press you?
You have to imitate this kind of thing to do
I can show you some of the things I did later
You see, I can get this kind of seam line very well
This kind of plate and plate pressure edge
And this kind of thickness can be solved very well
Including you see this kind of place
I will copy a layer inside
Maybe this is not the video intensity
I don't feel very high
You see, I choose one inside this
Then I will copy a layer
I will copy a layer
Then I select all of them to squeeze in a little bit
Also under control plus middle
Then flip the line
Then I combine the two of them
Then for example this
I do some of this kind of bridge
Then put all of them into a bridge
You see, I got a thickness
Because a lot of people want me to do all of them
So I want to reduce some faces
So I copied a little bit
I just let my thickness be a little bit
I don't have anything that I can't see inside
Because if there is, I will waste a lot of life
If you do this, I will save face
Save face
Including this edge
You can use this UV selection method
For example, I choose a circle line
Then do some bevel
Then you can adjust this value a little bit
All of these things feel that in the future
If there is a lot of things
There may be a little bit of lag
A little bit of lag
But I think just like I just said
You do anything
You have to be a little bit more careful
You will get a better effect
This is not the same as the bevel algorithm
Not the same
I don't feel the bevel is the same
Because it is done according to some of the things you find
I don't really use some of the bevels
Including here
You see, I will choose some of the lines of this outer circle
You see, squeeze inwards
You see, now there is one
Maybe the video is not very clear
There is a small structure here
Then you see
I will add another side
Including this
I also have the same reason
Let it have some changes
You see
There is a small structure here
All things
According to this
Let's take a look at the real physical world
Including this
I will consider some things that are lagging
I will put this place a little bit
Lock it
Because I want this corner to be straighter
So everyone still has to understand
For the game
May need you to understand a little bit
This kind of knowledge of lagging
Then still have to ensure that it is a thing on all four sides
This is the case
OK
Right
Lock this thing
Then go on
I will take this
For example, this kind of edge
Go in and lock it
I will be a little faster
All are made in the same way
Just spend some time on it
It will be better
Then go in and squeeze inwards
Go in and squeeze inwards
Increase thickness
Then squeeze inwards
You see
So I get a better one
A good effect
Right
Over this edge
A reason
I'm fast
So I get a better one
A good effect
Then you see
Integrate the body
Right
Get a
This edge
a very good edge, a texture.
A lot of people just want to
put this model directly into ZB,
and I get everything.
But if you do a little bit of operation in Maya,
you will get some very good effects, right?
You see, there is also this kind of thickness.
In fact, it can take some more time
to make this kind of edge.
I should have done it, too.
This kind of edge
can be squeezed in a little bit,
and then this is an effect of pressing the edge.
It is done according to our real clothes.
In fact, if you want to say that it is a high-end model,
it is also a high-end model.
If you want to carve a little bit more in ZB,
it's okay to deal with it a little bit.
You see,
you can squeeze this kind of edge out a little bit.
Because when we are making clothes,
there is also a small thickness pressed down here.
In fact, many times you need to observe all of this in life.
How do you sew clothes?
This is what everyone needs to observe.
Including this kind of place,
you see, I will use a manual way to do some,
you see, I will use a manual way to do some sewing.
You can also use Bible to do it.
I remember that the file seems to be broken.
You may not have seen it just now.
This one, this one, this one, the lower right corner.
That's why I saw it a long time ago.
In fact, everyone has seen it before.
Maybe you have seen it before.
You may know it.
I've seen one about how to adjust the line of the marvelous diesebrush.
That thing I think I should be the first to do this kind of video.
But then many apps are doing it in this way.
I might be our attention to the level,
maybe there is no Apple attention to the level of high.
That's the first way I did it.
Then I'm not doing it that way anymore,
because just like this one just dropped.
The pattern between the panels is different,
but with this method, you can get a better result.
Then you have to do this kind of card line,
you will get some better results.
Then I will use this kind of Maya carving brush
to make some adjustments in some places.
This is basically a small case of Maya adjustment.
It takes some time to do this kind of thing.
Everything requires everyone to do this kind of thing quietly and carefully.
Then I want to show you a little bit,
how much time is left?
There is still 5-6 minutes.
Because many times, for example, in doing projects,
sometimes you have already done it to this extent,
but you still have a lot of work to do.
You hope that the customer has changed,
or that the clothes have been pulled up,
or that there are some other changes.
But I have already done this 5-6 minutes,
how can I do it?
I can't re-card the sides,
re-do some lines, right?
Then the next part is this part.
Then we go back to the state of our mavler.
For example, the customer asks me to pull it over here,
or the sleeves have changed a little bit.
What should I do?
I want to do this.
The customer says, I want to do this.
Or I want to do this in the project.
Right?
Including this sleeve.
Because I have a relatively large list,
it is 6.
So, relatively speaking,
it is also a bit more difficult to do.
Because of this method,
I think I have used it for a long time.
I think I can get a very good result.
I think I can get a very clean model.
It is also relatively simple for entering JB later.
Because it has UV.
If you add a little bit of this texture to JB later,
it will also get a better effect.
Because you can't brush a very fine texture.
I have some pictures for everyone to take a look at later.
For example, you see,
the customer requires all things to become like this.
But my model is already done.
What should I do?
I'll go first.
I'll pull it out.
I'll just pull one out first.
You see.
I will export this model.
But you must remember to save it.
The model before we turn the triangle.
The model before you turn the four sides.
You have to keep it, too.
Remember to save more files.
Don't cover it.
And then include this model.
Also export.
You see.
If I do this,
there are two models.
My model is just like the body.
Just like the body.
I'll import my model.
You see.
This is the model.
These two models.
I'll give it a different material.
Make it look clearer.
Because this model and this model are all triangles.
I can give them a blend shape.
You see.
I can let my model become this model.
Can you understand this?
And then.
At this time.
I'll go through this rock.
And then choose the model we just made.
I'm going to add it to this.
Then choose a model with the same three edges.
and add it to the model.
Because this model is driven by this model.
It may need you to understand this thing.
Then I will use our final model
and the model in front of us to make a blend shape.
See, I directly drive my model.
This is the model I made.
I will copy a new one.
I will open my model later.
See, it will automatically make some changes with it.
Because it is driven, right?
If you understand some of the principles of animation,
you can understand this kind of thing.
Then I copy a new one.
This is Hero Pose 2.
Let's set it back.
I need to return it to its original state.
And remove the history.
Ok, let's save it.
For now, I will be doing this.
The second part is only this.
Well,
I haven't remade this model, but I can get this model.
Can you see it?
This can be driven.
After you get one, you just need to change the MD.
As long as you haven't changed the size and UV of the board,
you can have this operation.
But if you have problems with the board,
you can't do it.
After all, two things need to have the same mother object.
That's how you get this effect.
Look at this.
And in this case, I'm going to open my computer.
I'm Maya.
Let me tell you which one it is.
Let me turn on Maya.
This is something that came out after Maya 2020.
And before 19, it didn't exist.
19 is RAP.
RAP, sometimes when your computer is not very good,
you will basically get stuck.
UV transmission.
The overall transmission of UV transmission will be wrong, right?
Not necessarily.
I actually did it in the way of UV transmission at the beginning.
But now I rarely use UV transmission.
So, I don't really use this.
The other thing is,
I can't use the UV transmission function anymore.
I want to do it like a pump,
and pass it to the computer at full speed.
I understand why you want to use it.
But you can't.
I want to do it in a high speed.
But I don't have the ability to do it in high speed.
It doesn't work.
I want to have more than the same speed.
This is why I bought it.
It's good to have more than the same speed.
I use it at high speed for a long time.
But you have to be more careful.
Add a little bit more speed.
Let me get going.
I'm a little stuck.
You can figure out how to do it in 1 second.
If I had more speed,
and if I had more speed,
Do you think that I will still pass on my skills? No, I don't think so, I don't use that method anymore.
I don't know if it will be related to advertising.
Because when you are giving lectures, you need to update some of the techniques.
It's impossible for me to teach these people one thing at a time.
Because you also want to have some better methods to improve efficiency.
So I'm not like other teachers.
I always have one method to do it.
I'm constantly improving my efficiency.
Because in the production of a project, you will find that your efficiency is very important.
And not everything depends on you, right?
Look, these two are all inspired by Marvel.
Right?
This is something I made up.
I just adjusted some of the poses and poured them in, right?
And then I did the blend shape.
This is understandable, right?
I remember Max should also do that kind of move.
In the editor.
Yes, it's the same as the 3D Max move.
Look, I have a pose.
There is a pose.
There is a pose before the pose.
And then there is a blend shape in this deform.
Point.
Because they are basically the same object.
You can do this blend shape.
Just like animation.
If you make an animation, you will know this kind of thing.
Let me delete it.
Then I put the hero in.
I put it back to the original position.
Because you see, our hero is based on this.
I just said to move.
Because I made some adjustments to my body.
So it's still the same.
So its position is basically the same.
Right?
This is understandable, right?
Its position is the same.
So one of its principles is my model.
To wrap this model.
To drive it.
So one of the previous methods is to choose a model of this hero.
It's a default model that we made.
There is a wrap in the deform.
This model is called wrap.
But it will be stuck.
When your computer is not very good.
It's stuck.
Is it effective if the UV in the back is changed?
Yes.
Because of this thing.
You see, the UV of my model must be.
There must be a problem, right?
After this is stuck.
My UV must be like this.
It's already very messy.
I can also talk about UV.
You see, it's already super messy.
This is all wrong.
I just said.
This kind of thing has been moved out.
I can choose all of these things.
Because it is squeezed out.
Its UV becomes like this.
If you understand UV.
You should understand it, right?
You can move it out separately.
Then you right click.
You can directly give it a mapping.
You can directly give it a flat projection.
Look.
So I got one.
I turn it off.
Turn it off.
You see.
I got one.
This UV.
Right?
This is the default UV.
This is my later UV.
I just do a little bit.
You can understand it.
Then.
Because it has a very good loop.
So I choose here.
For example, choose its front line.
I can choose cut.
Then I choose UV here.
UV Shell.
I can move it over.
Right?
But you will find.
They are separated.
I just need to.
Just sew this UV here.
Then.
How to do it?
For example.
I choose a edge.
Choose a edge.
You see.
This edge.
Right?
I have one under this UV.
In modify.
I start to modify.
Or.
Here.
There is a seam.
I just sew it.
Then.
Double click.
Select all UVs.
Then.
Re-select.
This is the selection.
I just need to right click.
I fold.
It comes over.
You see.
UV is done.
See.
I just need to do this in other places.
Then.
My UV is done.
If you do a project.
I also get a good UV.
Can you understand?
Very convenient.
Then.
Go back to our default state.
Now.
After 2010.
It has one.
Just.
Go back to RAP.
At this time.
It updated a little bit.
It has one.
This RAP.
This is an added thing.
Very good.
You just need to click.
Then.
Control A.
Output it.
A menu.
You edit it.
A node.
Then.
Here.
You just need to.
Remove.
Select.
You need to.
Add.
The one we chose.
Then.
Re-select.
Here.
I'm here.
In this drive.
Driver.
You add this.
So.
Now.
My D-Mode.
Drive.
This model.
You see.
When I do D-Mode.
It has a connection.
See.
They have a connection.
So.
I'm going to.
Drag this out.
Ah.
Fire.
Display.
So.
In this.
In this case.
I can.
Ah.
Let me see.
Which one.
Hide them first.
There are more.
Things.
I choose.
My.
This model.
Then.
Choose.
My.
This model.
I'll hide it first.
This.
Because.
I established.
A relationship.
Because.
Choosing.
This control shape.
It's all the same.
You don't ask.
This kind of technical question.
You see.
I choose this.
To them.
Do a.
Blend shape.
You see.
Now.
I.
Operate it.
Hey.
It has changed.
Right.
But.
We just.
Used.
This.
Because.
They.
Have.
This.
Connection.
So.
When I.
Do.
You see.
I.
This.
High.
Door.
Follows.
Move together.
Because.
It's.
Raw.
Look.
I.
Have.
This.
Operation.
Understand.
This.
Is.
My.
Original.
But.
I.
Still.
Want.
A.
Little.
Change.
How.
To.
Say.
You see.
I.
These.
Two.
Can.
Do.
A.
Blend.
Shape.
This.
And.
Choose.
This.
Point.
I.
Like.
A.
Middle.
Right.
But?
I.
Can.
What.
Say.
I.
This.
Is.
The.
Only.
Here.
No.
Thing.
I.
Have.
Some.
This.
Time.
Blank.
It.
Has.
No.
Shape.
I don't need to change it. I only need to change this part, but not this part.
Then I can add
replace,
which means cancel the selection.
I can choose this one.
I can fill it in black.
Look, there are some errors here, right?
I only need to make it smoother.
I can fill it in black
to make it smoother.
Look, I only need to change this part,
but not this part.
You can use a wide range of applications.
It's not that hard.
You only need to spend some time.
You can get a lot of good results.
Someone just said
it's not that hard, right?
Let's do it like this.
I'll do it quickly.
Are there any other questions?
No.
.
how to change it? For example, merge the two of them first.
For example, you will see it later.
Then I go to remove, let it be on both sides.
Then I go to get, zoom in a little bit, let it be a little bit bigger.
OK, then delete, then get, then delete.
Let's going to
This is live, the broadcast is not accelerated.
lock confirm.
You see, I got this model, I see, this one is not integrated.
Then you see, I got one of these, right?
I want to make a cloud, how to do it?
For example, move it a little bit, move it a little bit, move it a little bit.
Then the same principle, I'm going to do this kind of collection.
For example, there will be some collections in the cloud, right?
Including this thing, I can also do a little bit.
Bubble Syrup Queue.
Actually, I think a lot of times I will have a doubt.
That is, many people think that MD is omnipotent.
I can, I can do everything with MD.
In fact, don't have this kind of idea.
I think any software has a good place for it and a bad place for it.
You don't have to think about everything.
I do everything with MD.
I think sometimes you have to think about it.
You have to consider its rationality.
OK.
You see the same.
I put all the frames open and freeze.
OK.
Reset freeze.
Thank you.
Wait, wait.
Wait for me to finish this.
You see what kind of questions there are.
ah
d
Do MD.
Clothes sewing.
Later.
I'll give you a thought.
Don't worry.
One by one.
I'm because I'm doing this when I also have no way to watch the chat, right?
Yes Yes
We can use chats, right?
Okay.
And on this basis, we...
Is it okay?
It's okay, Brother Qiang.
We will reply to chats.
It's just that I can't reply to chats all of a sudden.
I'll let Jimmy reply.
Okay.
Look.
Let's make it a little shorter.
This is understandable, right?
Let's make it simple.
And then, look.
On this basis, let's make it a little...
The one with the Yaw.
I'll just do it.
Offset, internal line.
Here.
5.
Okay.
Look.
He didn't connect the two sides.
We just need to right click.
This is it.
Look.
I got it.
Let me show you the internal line first.
I got this.
And then...
Or...
I will get one of these things, right?
But what about the羽絨符?
I use the same method to copy one.
Copy one, for example, I want to go out, over.
I copy an outer layer, can you understand?
If we choose this thing, I put it back.
Don't let it have the same color.
Choose a red one.
Then I hide it.
Look, this is the inside.
I hope the inside is inverted.
That is, one goes in and one goes out.
Right click.
Flip normal.
Wait a moment.
It needs to be inverted.
Look.
The inside goes to the body.
Then the outside goes here.
I have to show it.
Look at this.
I got a model like this.
But I put it a little bit more.
For example, 90.
Pull it a little bit.
I got a model like this.
You find that this is not the effect of the羽絨符.
I hide it like this.
For it, I make it a little bit smaller.
95.
65.
Because if it is like this,
it shrinks.
Or 90.
95.
90.
Shrinks it.
You see, if I do 5, it means that the object is moving inside the body, because the object is in the opposite direction.
If I do an expansion, the object will definitely expand inside the body.
Can you understand this?
And for the outside, I also do 5.
Because if you do this, the object will move inside the body, and the outside will move outside the body, so the object will not fly.
For example, I can make this a little bigger, 10.
This is also 10.
It will expand.
Then we add a new one.
Change the material.
Change one.
I can do it in any form you want.
For example, I choose a Shining.
Change the material.
You see, now we have a new model of the羽絨服.
And then I found out that...
I don't need to use Chinese, I'm sorry.
And then you will find that our example is still very...
So we can use a slightly lower example.
For example, use an 8.
It's starting to have that texture now.
But it's not that obvious yet.
So in this case, we need to change a material.
For example, I'm going to use green.
I can use a nylon one.
See? The small wrinkles are slowly coming out.
And in this case, you want this horizontal...
I want...
I have some wrinkles here.
What should I do?
For example, I choose these two pieces.
Horizontal.
I need...
I can...
For example, horizontal.
I'll expand it.
See? It's bigger horizontally.
This way, there are more wrinkles.
You need to know how to get the wrinkles you want
through this ratio relationship.
You can control it through this thing.
Can you see?
For example,
generally,
depending on how good your computer is,
I sometimes adjust it to 3 or 2 or 1.
It depends on your computer.
If your computer is good,
you can adjust it very finely.
If your computer is bad,
there's no way.
There's no way.
If your computer is good,
you can adjust it very finely.
If your computer is bad,
there's no way.
You need to be very careful.
I'll think about it.
Then I'll...
It lags.
When the time of 2 and 3 comes,
it definitely lags.
I can...
I make it 1.
Good.
See, you can get some fine effects.
You see?
Some of you asked
what to do with the emboss.
I can do it through...
然后把内部线关掉,然后空选所有的缝线,我可以在这儿去加缝线,去加缝线。
只希望缝线附近出现小褶皱。
那就像我说的,你可以通过一些,做两个形态,然后通过其他的一些Maya或者什么去刷Blend Shape,对吧?
你可以这样。
你看,你可以调整这种大小啊,比如说1.5,或者是……
你看,你可以去增加这种东西,比如说这个Offset什么的都可以,我记得可以调整。
对,就看你。
其实缝线是可以导出去的啊,你可以把这个缝线导从OBG文件出去的啊,你可以很好的去导出去。
可以这样,这么来做。
看。
是可以,可以搞定的啊。
这是,你看羽绒服多简单,是不是?
没有你们想象那么难,就是很多东西都是很简单。
没有你想象那么难啊,实际上。
古风衣服是一样的,你只是去,因为这种打板也是很多的,对吧?
各种各样的打板也是很多的啊。
还有其他的一些问题嘛,我也讲了小两个小时。
大家如果有什么特别MD像的,或者一些就是不是特别行的,
是特别写实比较抽象的那一些,可以等一下我来回,没关系的。
对。
对,因为你从我的一些作品来看,我基本上全是写实的一些东西,武装的我做的很少。
就是当时在做,可能我们在做天刀的时候,我用过一点点MD,不多。
就是像这些东西用过一点点,真的不是很多。
包括你看,这种方法,我处理模型的方法。
对于这个我会应用的更多一点。
我当时做小岛的这个东西的时候,我会应用的更多一点。
所有的,你看这些边,我都是玛雅来做的。
这些小的这种边缘呢,全是玛雅来做的。
这些,你压着我,我压着你这种边。
因为这种东西,如果说你不这么来做,你会CB里去刷,没办法刷的这么整齐。
没办法刷这么整齐。
这是最终的一个效果。
是这样,这是游戏模型。
还有别的一些问题吗?
对,其实古风来讲也是,前期拿MD来做,后期还要去修正。
不可能完全一下就好了。
强哥也是辛苦了两个小时。
没事,没事。
但会有一些问题可以等一下我来回的,没关系。
嗯,OK,OK。
你要不给大家展示一下你以前的作品,或者打打广告什么的。
嗯,广告,大家可以关注我的那个bilibili啊。
然后如果说你们有什么想看的,对于我这个背包啊,还有这个都是有教程在售卖的,就是光书的,你们可以去CCTalk搜。
我也很少打广告。
因为大家如果知道的,一般也都知道我了。
可以到光书这儿,去搜我的这两个。
可以去搜光书啊,然后有这个Mobler的一个做这个的教程。
你可以通过这个东西学到很多,很多小的技巧。
虽然不是别的,然后可以学到很多小的技巧,包括这种,这种,这种防弹背心。
然后我的Pinterest就是,你可以到Pinterest搜我的这个名字,加一个John小,然后save,是这样。
这样一个东西。
其实很多时候我会把MD的东西再进行一些Zbrush的一些,一些细化来做。
然后这个就是当时,刚才Sino说。
我在Subtance一个新版本发布的时候,给他们做的一个demo。
这个角色,我所有的衣服也是在Mobler来做的。
然后所有的材质是通过Subtance来做的。
这个模型没有进行过任何的Zbrush。
就是我MD算之后,我会在马雅中做一个清理。
你看我所有东西都做了一点点清理。
这个角色是我自己,我有一个扫描的一个模型。
然后我去做了一个清理。
然后其实你要花一些时间在上面,你可以把这个布线做得很好。
但是你需要去马雅中,我去可能重新布线,卡线去修正一下。
我可以把这个模型做得非常的工整。
基本上就这样。
然后这是一个UV的一个展示。
你看Mobler里一个效果。
你看包括这个东西,我都是在Mobler里来做的。
这个车牌的一个硬的东西,我是在Mobler里来做的。
包括你看这个角色。
这个角色我当时做的时候。
这个狗牌我是Mobler做的。
这个牌都是挂着的线。
因为这种垂坠感,你去解算的话,你会放的话,你会感觉不自然。
但是你去通过Mobler,你可以给它做得非常的好。
然后其他的,包括帽子,你看,都可以Mobler。
所有都是Mobler来做。
书包,这个书包其实还是很细致的。
这个书包。
看这个书包上所有东西都是Mobler。
看这个很细小的一些东西。
只要一点点。
呵呵。
头发很难做。
这个就是另一个东西了。
就和这个没有太多关系了。
今天的一个课程。
包括你看,这个东西都是Mobler。
而且你去我的bilibili,你可以看到这种小的技巧。
比如说,我把视频关掉。
你看,这些小的东西,如何去通过这个。
你可以到我的B站来去观看。
这个东西怎么去做。
都是有一些小技巧。
我刚听到不是很多Mobler,主要是一些雕刻的一些东西。
然后其他的我觉得没有太多要讲的。
这是我当时在Mobler比赛的时候做的一个东西。
但是这个很早了,现在看着也不太好看。
但是当时可能参加的人也不多吧。
然后我这个东西只做了,但是运气比较好。
我只做了两天,好像两个晚上。
然后得了奖了。
很开心。
得了一个显示器,一个Mobler的一个版权。
因为还包括你看这些东西都是,有些东西都是Mobler来去进行一些制作的。
包括一些硬的这种感觉,都是可以来实现的。
然后我会花一些时间在这个上面。
你会看到,你看这个模型就是这种Mobler导出来的。
然后去进行一些清理。
然后其他地方都是卡线的。
因为我的工作就是在有些阶段里是做。
影视嘛。
可能大家也可以关注我的微博。
因为有很多影视的东西你不会放出来。
但是我看看我做的几部电影。
平时我也是,我更喜欢就是硬表面的一些东西。
我可以去看一下。
包括你看有些朋友刚才说卡线的一些事情。
这是游戏的一些低门了。
游戏的一些低门。
你看我比较喜欢卡线。
我会花很多时间在这个卡线上面。
我会把它卡的更好点。
包括分UV啊什么的。
然后这是我做的光束。
然后你看狗牌对吧Mobler来做。
你只需要给它加一个厚度让它硬度。
然后去做这种东西去得到这个效果。
包括你看所有东西都是Mobler来去做。
通过几层东西来去弄。
然后我做的电影。
这是我做几个电影。
我不知道大家看过几部啊。
你可以看完之后有那个最后的演员表有我的名字啊。
这是Maze Runner。
这个是移动迷宫。
然后这个我也做了寡姐的一些东西。
然后致命引擎。
然后这个猎鹰与东兵。
我做的猎鹰的一个衣服在电影里。
因为我之前是在VitaDigital工作。
然后包括这个还有这个还有这个项目。
我做的这个小女孩的一些东西。
包括最近在上映的这个我做了很多这些主角的衣服。
我都做了好几个这个项目。
然后包括我还做过动画电影。
不知道有多少人看过这个电影。
然后这是几部还有一部没放出来。
就是阿凡达二。
其他的没什么了吧。
就是我有交流群。
但是交流群基本上大家都进不去。
因为它一直是一个满源的一个状态。
没精致。
就这样吧。
但是光束太厉害了。
我只是也是工作嘛。
差不多就这样。
好。
好的。
辛苦强哥了。
没事。
强哥一个人懒了一半我的活。
本来我要回弹幕的。
我看到有个弹幕说强哥你能退一下群让我进去吗?
可以。
可以的。
好的。
那辛苦强哥了。
没事。
期待下一次合作。
谢谢强哥。
好的。
拜拜。
再见。
谢谢。
我来看一下之前大家的一些问题好吧。
稍等一下。
嗯。
我把它拉出来。
强哥确实是六边形战士。
我看一下我之前有哪些问题。
嗯。
If you want to have a vertical fold, then you should stretch it horizontally, and the opposite is the same.
Someone asked before, can the MD version be used for work cloth?
It's best not to. If you want to use it in the factory, our company has another software called Claw.
Then you can pay attention to it, it also has an account on Bilibili.
How to make a hard color in MD?
First of all, we have some videos on how to make a hard color in MD.
Including the military uniform that Jimmy did before.
You can do it in other ways.
For example, you can fold it with the inner line, or you can do it from the angle of the wrinkle line.
Then you can make a hard color.
You can also make a hard color by folding it in a vertical fold.
You can also make a hard color.
You can also make a hard color by folding it in a horizontal fold.
It is an important step in making a hard color in MD.
You can also make a hard color in MD.
Actually, as long as you understand how the layer is made,
then you can change it wherever you need to make it bigger.
Let me take a look at the new demo.
It should have been destroyed before.
If you search for Hanfu, you will find a lot of that kind of costume.
And actually, we haven't seen a lot of it in the game.
It's actually not a Hanfu version.
It has a lot of fantasy-like clothes.
It's the kind of clothes that come out of the brain.
If it's a costume that comes out of the brain,
you can make some other changes on the Hanfu version.
For example, where it's wider, you can make it wider.
Ah, yes, we are one family.
And don't ask for the file again.
The previous file has already been answered.
Now we have also processed the user name of the file.
I don't recommend making a hard surface in MD.
If you want to do it, you can only make some simple hard surfaces.
For example, it doesn't have any kind of凹凸 and carving.
The most basic ones can be made.
But afterwards, you still have to go to other software to carve.
Right?
Don't use real names.
No, no, no.
No need to force the name.
You can also use the real name.
We'll have a draw later.
Uh, the original painting.
Yes, it is said that sometimes you can't force it in MD.
It's the same as the original painting.
Because the original painting often has its own ideas.
Then what we are going to do is to make a large similar one in MD.
It's similar to the outline.
But the details are the best.
There are some particularly anti-physical.
For example,
It is a very loose pants.
But it also has very fine and tight folds.
That is,
You have to make some carvings.
Or do some compression effects.
Uh, then,
I'll take a look at one.
This one.
Uh, the exciting part.
Wait a minute.
I'll turn on the background music.
I'll start to draw.
Ah, but don't brush the demo.
Brushing the demo is useless.
Uh, the pressure is not good.
I can't do it now.
Yes, if it's based on the original painting,
Don't care about the board.
I wanted to put a
That one
Kabuda
But I don't know what the name of Kabuda's stick is.
Uh, there is a special music for raffle.
It's not this kind.
Oh, it's good luck.
That is, first of all, we want to congratulate.
Uh, let's congratulate first.
That is,
I just finished answering this question.
To the children of the raffle.
Let's look at one.
Uh, this one.
Work table.
Ah, Excel.
Ah, here it is.
Good.
Uh, there is a number here.
That was just hard and secret.
I have already processed these users.
This information.
Uh, if there is no fill.
Just like this friend.
If you don't fill that.
Uh, the mailbox.
Uh, it's.
It's not working.
Uh, that's it.
I can't draw it.
Um.
Yes.
Then.
Let's come.
I'll show you first.
Oh, there's that one in Excel.
He has that one.
Draw random numbers.
This is a.
What is this called?
A code of random numbers.
I'll show you first.
It's absolutely correct.
For example, we are 300.
Because we don't have 300 people.
Oh, this is before.
There is a question in the bottom left corner of the bulletin board.
Uh, you'll see yours later.
There must be yours.
What?
I.
Until this.
Uh.
When we finish this.
There are only 137 people.
Yes.
Okay.
Then.
I.
Taking pictures of 30 members.
Oh, this.
I.
The person is.
su씨e.
I.
Brilliantly delighted.
Let's do it again, okay?
1 to 137
No need to send a comment
Now is the time to announce the winner
The winner's time
Okay, fill in the form and you can participate
Wait a minute, do I need to turn on the camera?
Oops, I can't point the mouse to the side
I'll just point it to the side
This ending will come out
Okay, it's okay
The exciting moment is here
1 to 137
Let's see which number is a new user
Okay, 96
Okay, let's start
Uh, this question is just
If you participate in the live broadcast
You should be able to see it
Because we have
We've been talking about it from the beginning
Uh, the reward is Huawei's flat version
And Marvelous Designer's annual
This license
Uh 97
96, sorry
Let's take a look at 96
Yes, the blood number is...
Wait, let's take a look
Is it?
The blood number should end at 137
Ah, the blood number is 138
Oh, sorry, it's 138
But it's already over, I don't care
It's 96, alright?
1 to 96
Ahaha
Oh no, oh no, oh no, no, no, no, no
It's impossible to open it again
It's impossible, alright?
Let's congratulate this person
Chen... Chen...
Chenxin
user
QQ number is 7911
The number at the start
There will be weird songs
Wait until the sky turns yellow
It will come back and ask me to go home
Let's see
It starts with weird songs
Sorry, sorry
How do these results come about?
We just sent an announcement
That is
To scan the QR code
Okay
Ah, I'm sorry, I'm sorry. The song list was exposed.
Okay, congratulations to this person with the surname Chen.
It's okay, he's not here, we'll also notify him backstage, okay? This user.
Congratulations.
This is this person with the surname Chen, and then 791 at the beginning.
User.
How to receive this? We will contact him ourselves, because he wrote the Q number.
There won't be another chance.
Everyone can participate, and look forward to the future live broadcasts, okay?
No, I'm thinking, why didn't you all come when we were giving out things before?
Then let's end it here for today, friends.
We don't have a raffle every time we do a live broadcast.
Uh, there shouldn't be any.
The second prize, you go to the QQ group and think about me, or you think about me backstage, okay?
Just call me in the QQ group.
I will send a Bilibili official notification later.
I will send it in our dynamic.
Then the first prize, this user, we will call and notify this user.
Okay.
Um.
It's okay, families.
There will be more in the future.
Okay?
Um.
And all the friends who filled out this form, you don't have to worry.
In the future, if there is an opening class, we will notify you first.
Okay?
I understand everything.
After that, there will be this live broadcast.
If there is a raffle or something, it is best to be able to ensure that it is all there.
And then we should have a notice hanging on the bottom left corner.
Um.
Uh, I didn't find you.
This must be yours.
It won't leak.
Oh, it doesn't matter.
You didn't fill it this time.
We will also release it.
Okay?
Um.
If you have any questions, you can add our WeChat group in the bottom left corner.
Uh, what WeChat group?
QQ group.
Um.
If you have any questions, you can ask us in there.
But on Sunday, we may not be there.
Ahaha.
Right.
Um.
How about we end it here today?
Okay.
See you next time, friends.
Okay?
Live broadcast.
The live broadcast this time will be a little later.
Okay.
See you next time.
The brother of 2 live broadcasts.
Hurry up and come back.
Hanna.
Uh, the adjuster.
Um.
It's over today.
Let me open the camera.
Goodbye, everyone.
Bye bye bye bye.
Bye bye bye.
Goodbye, everyone.
Bye bye.
Why bye.
Bye bye bye.
Good.
Goodbye everyone.
Bye bye.
Md official account is今mi.
Say goodbye with kit.
All right, Goodbye.
Bye bye .
A familyikast asks hanna to be barracks for you discovered by all friends.
Today is over.
Okay, bye-bye
Bye-bye, bye-bye, bye-bye, bye-bye, bye-bye, bye-bye, bye-bye, bye-bye
Bye-bye, bye-bye
Bye-bye
That Chuan Chuan person
You won the prize, you know?
Why haven't you come to my place to receive the prize?
Oh, bye-bye, bye-bye
Yes, I've finished drawing
Bye-bye
Bye-bye, everyone, goodbye, bye-bye
Goodbye, goodbye, bye-bye
Bye-bye
Oh, okay, okay, okay, okay
Okay, bye-bye, everyone, goodbye, bye-bye
See you next time, bye-bye
Hey, Ximo, bye-bye, bye-bye
Goodbye, teacher, bye-bye